<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>alessandro vitali</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on alessandro vitali</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HEC</title><link>/works/hec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/works/hec/</guid><description>The Habitable Exoplanets Catalog (HEC) is an online database of potentially habitable worlds discoveries for scientists, educators, and the general public. A potentially habitable exoplanet implies a planet outside our solar system with conditions roughly comparable to those of Earth and thus potentially favourable to earth-like life.
Japan, so fascinating and yet sometimes so unexplicable for us, takes on a new perspective: an exoplanet in which life has taken a different turn, but still similar to our.</description></item><item><title>Hortus Conclusus</title><link>/works/hortus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/works/hortus/</guid><description>Site-specific installation for a.topos gallery, Hortus Conclusus is an artistic intervention intended to dialogue with the gallery space, with the city of Venice and its structure. By Hortus conclusus we mean a green area, usually small in size, surrounded by high walls, in which monks cultivated plants and trees. Green spaces in Venice have always been confined on islands or in small allotments, private or public such as the Parco delle Rimembranze in Sant’Elena.</description></item><item><title>Marine Snow</title><link>/works/marine-snow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/works/marine-snow/</guid><description>Marine snow refers to a continuous rain of organic and inorganic particles that falls from the upper layers of the water column. The particles that constitute marine snow are so called because of the way they appear, flakes that fall in the darkness of the deep sea.
This work is a collection of photographs from 2018 to 2023, from my personal archive of travels, assignments, private moments, friends and strangers. It covers the period from the death of my father in 2018 to the death of my mother at the end of 2023.</description></item><item><title>Orti di guerra</title><link>/works/orti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/works/orti/</guid><description>A century after the establishment of commemorative monuments and parks built in Italy in the aftermath of the First World War to honour the fallen, a project initiated by the ICCD in Rome raises questions around the theme of the monument and memory by proposing a selection of contemporary works. These are the result of heterogeneous projects ranging from documentary photography to illustration.
The War Garden is a herbarium consisting of vegetables and fruits grown in war gardens at the time of the First World War.</description></item><item><title>Proposta</title><link>/works/proposta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/works/proposta/</guid><description>“Put flowers in your guns” it’s the beginning of a song from I giganti, Proposta, presented at the Sanremo Music Festival of italian song in 1967. Flowers, nature, weapons. Two antithetical concepts, often used in opposition to each other: good and evil. But nature and weapons also speak to us about individuals, about choices and above all of communities, bringing us back to an ancestral nature, to manual skills that we are gradually forgetting.</description></item></channel></rss>